João Victor Caetano

Ernesto Zuanella, 81 - Parque 1 Continental, SP	ñ
+55(11) 96951-8790	L
jcaetano@usp.br	V
linkedin.com/in/joao-victor-olive ira-caetano-8416a41b0	in

Bachelor of Molecular Sciences from the University of São Paulo (USP) with experience in software development and data analysis, modeling, and project management. Proficient in multiple programming languages, mathematical logic, and solving complex problems.

Work Experience

FEBRUARY, 2023 - CURRENTLY

Jr. Automation and Data Analyst/J.V.C. Instalação e Manutenção Elétrica LTDA. Data analysis, process automation, VBA, Python, Power BI, software development, infrastructure, logistics, and project coordination. I managed service logistics, budget automation, profit and cost analysis for renovations of public and state schools in São Paulo.

JANUARY, 2018 - CURRENTLY

Teacher in Mathematics and Biological Sciences

I taught classes for college entrance exam preparation and provided academic support for high school and higher education students.

AUGUST, 2020 — AUGUST, 2023

Undergraduate Research in Nuclear Physics (High Energy)/Mathematical Physics Laboratory, University of São Paulo (USP)

Leading a scientific project in collaboration with other teams. Through statistics, data analysis, modeling, dashboard creation, extensive knowledge of programming languages, algorithm efficiency, and solutions for complex problems.

Skills

Python (Pandas, SeaBorn, Matplotlib, Numpy, Astropy Glob e mais) • C/C++/C# • R • Java/JavaScript • HTML• SQL • VBA • PowerBI • Pacote Office • Automation • Machine Learning • Cloud • IA • Data Analyst • Math • Physics • Aws Glue • Aws Sagamaker • Advanced English

Education

FEBRUARY, 2023

Bachelor of Molecular Sciences/ University of São Paulo (USP).

The course offers comprehensive training in chemistry, biology, physics, computer science, and mathematics, distinguished by a practical approach in state-of-the-art laboratories. Students actively participate in research projects, working with renowned professors and researchers. The curriculum includes subjects such as Algorithms, Numerical Calculus, Statistics, and Quantum Mechanics.

Project Evaluator at the Feira Brasileira de Ciência e Engenharia(FEBRACE)/University of São Paulo (USP)

The Brazilian Science and Engineering Fair/Feira Brasileira de Ciência e Engenharia (FEBRACE) is a program aimed at nurturing talent in science and engineering. Its purpose is to promote a scientific culture, stimulate investigative thinking, foster innovation, and encourage entrepreneurship among young people and educators in basic, higher, and technical education throughout Brazil. The evaluators applied critical thinking when analyzing participants' projects, classifying them into various categories and seeking those that were most innovative and aligned with current market demands.

Activities

- Participant of Simpósio Internacional de Iniciação Científica e Tecnológica da USP (SIICUSP) 2021
- Participant of Simpósio Internacional de Iniciação Científica e Tecnológica da USP (SIICUSP) 2022
- Participant of XLIV Reunião de Trabalho da Física Nuclear do Brasil 2022
- Article Author "Nonrelativistic and relativistic simple wave problems solved with Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics" Journal Physics Conf.Ser. 2340 (2022)(https://inspirehep.net/literature/2067346)